wpwhitesecurity.com 2019-06-30

# WP White Security Privacy Policy

This privacy notice sets forth how WP White Security uses your information and respects your privacy.

This notice regards our relationship with you as a website visitor and/or as a customer.

If you use our plugins, they might capture and store user data on the databases of your own websites. This notice does not pertain to the user data held on your own websites through your uses of our plugins. Depending on internal policies, or local or national regulations, you may need to disclose the data captured by our plugins on your own sites through your own site privacy notices.

 _This notice was last updated on 4 th June 2019._

## Who we are

This privacy notice applies to the website WPWhiteSecurity.com, which is a business site operated by 3R1C B.V. We are a company located in the Netherlands. (Tarweveld 5, 6617CD, Bergharen)

## What information we collect

### Customer service and contact forms

If you contact us with a customer service concern, we’ll do our best to help. This may involve us asking you for technical information about your website. Any information you give to us in the context of a support query will only be used by our internal team for as long as it takes to resolve your concern. We will log your support experience in our internal customer service system in case we need to follow up.

We don’t use any third parties for customer service, and we won’t pass your details to any.

If you fill in a contact form, the form will collect your name, email address and the other information you provide in the form. We only use this data to reply to you. We retain this data  for as long as it is necessary to respond to your message.

### Email lists and promotional messaging

While we’d love to keep you in the loop about our latest plugins and news, you will not receive any promotional messages from us unless you opt in to allow us to send them.

If you have opted in but are no longer interested in our promotional messages from us, you can unsubscribe by using the unsubscribe links in all our emails.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on articles or posts, the site collects the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it.[ The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here](https://automattic.com/privacy). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics to provide aggregated data about site usage. We do not aggregate this data with any other information for any reason.

### Cookies and third parties

Google Analytics uses third party cookies to facilitate the analytics. You can control these cookies through your browser settings.

Outside of Google Analytics, this site does not use any other third party cookies.

We may occasionally embed useful content such as videos from [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [tweets](https://twitter.com/en/privacy), etc. Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website. These services may collect your IP Address, your browser’s User Agent, store and retrieve cookies on your browser, embed additional third party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including correlating your interaction with the content with your account with that service, if you are logged in to that service. I recommend exercising your privacy rights directly through the services using the links above.

## Who we share your data with

Our web site is

  * Hosted on [Kinsta](https://www.wpwhitesecurity.com/refer/kinsta)
  * Backed up with [BlogVault online WordPress backup service](https://www.wpwhitesecurity.com/refer/blogvault/), which is located in the EU.

Several of our plugins are sold through [CodeCanyon](https://codecanyon.net/user/wp_white_security), a third party affiliate service. If you purchase one of our plugins there, your commercial relationship for the transaction will be with Envato. We will have no access to any of your financial or transactional data. Their privacy policy can be viewed [here](https://envato.com/privacy/). Your customer service relationship will be with us.

Our newsletter is hosted by Mailchimp. You can learn how they protect your data [here](https://mailchimp.com/gdpr/).

## How long we retain your data

We retain all customer transactional data indefinitely.

We retain website comments indefinitely unless you request otherwise.

We retain non-personal Google Analytics data for the past 26 months of website traffic.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of them. You can also request that we erase any personal data held about you on this website and in our databases. This does not include customer service or transactional data which we may be obliged to keep for other reasons, including financial reporting.

## Where I send your data

This site is hosted on Kinsta in the US. You can read their European data processing agreement [here](https://kinsta.com/legal/data-privacy-addendum/).

CodeCanyon, which we use to sell some of our plugins, is located in Australia.

## External Links

This website contains links to other websites. Some of these links are affiliate links. We do not share your data with any websites we link to.

## How you can find out more

If you have any questions or concerns about the ways we use your data, or this privacy notice, please contact us on +31 (0)24 2022 825 info[@wpwhitesecurity.com](mailto:privacy@wpwhitesecurity.com).
